♪Wind♪
♪ الرياح ♪
♪Incidentally blows away fascinating whispers of love♪
♪ يضرب عرضا بيادق الحب الرائعة ♪
♪Whispers of love♪
♪ حراس الحب ♪
♪Sound the best with loyalty to the only valentine♪
♪ دق أفضل بالولاء إلى الوصية الوحيدة ♪
♪The prosperous life♪
♪ الحياة المزدهرة ♪
♪Is when we are together all year round♪
♪ هو عندما نكون معا على مدار السنة ♪
♪For the rest of my life♪
♪ لبقية حياتي ♪
♪All I want is a perfect love with you♪
♪ كل ما أريد هو حبك المثالي ♪
♪I'll remain elegant for you all my life♪
♪ سأبقى أنيقة لك طوال حياتي ♪
♪Giving you my love little by little♪
♪ إعطائك حبي شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
♪I care for you with every piece of my heart♪
♪ أنا أهتم بك في كل قلبي ♪
♪And I miss you every day and night♪
♪ وأنا أشتاق إليك كل ليلة ♪
♪I'll be loyal to you in the best years of my life♪
♪ سأكون مخلصا لك في أفضل سنوات حياتي ♪
♪Melting love with gentle smiles♪
♪ تميّز الحب بالأعمدة الحمقاء ♪
♪I won't be afraid of anything♪
♪ لن أشعر بالخوف من أي شيء ♪
♪And I won't change my heart for you♪
♪ لن أغيّر قلبي من أجلك ♪
=Jade's Fateful Love=
= حب اليشم المؤلم =
=Episode 4=
= الحلقة 4 =
All you need to do is take orders.
كل ما عليك فعله هو أخذ الأوامر
The Prime Minister won't mistreat you.
رئيس الوزراء لن يسيء معاملتك
Mr. Wang, I'll count on you.
السيد وانغ، سأعتمد عليك
No problem.
لا مشكلة
This girl looks pretty.
هذه الفتاة تبدو جميلة
But she dances poorly.
لكنها لا ترقص كثيرا
Cheers, Mr. Zhang.
الهتافات، السيد تشانغ
Cheers.
نخبكم
Pretty, does it hurt?
جميلة، هل تؤلمك؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
Look.
انظر
Even such a terrible dancer
حتى هذه الراقصة الفظيعة
can work in the House of Romance.
يمكن أن تعمل في بيت الرومانسية
Sorry, officials.
آسف أيها المسؤولون
It's the first I've danced here for a living
إنها الأولى التي ارتأيت فيها العيش هنا
and seen bigwigs like you.
ورأى الأشرار مثلك
I can't help feeling nervous.
لا يسعني إلا أن أشعر بالتوتر
I'll go get some better girls here.
سأذهب لأحضر بعض الفتيات الأفضل هنا
- All right. - Go ahead.
- حسنًا - تفضل
Come on, Mr. Wang.
هيا يا سيد وانغ
Mr. Wang, another toast to you.
السيد وانغ، نخب أخرى لك
- Cheers. - Stop.
- نخبكم - توقفي
Cheers.
الهتافات
You seductive fox!
أيها الثعلب المغري!
How dare you play innocent in front of me?
كيف تجرؤ على لعب الأبرياء أمامي؟
My husband keeps coming here lately.
يظل زوجي يأتي إلى هنا في الآونة الأخيرة
You must have seduced him.
لا بد أنك أغويته
Or why would he come here every day?
أو لماذا يأتي إلى هنا كل يوم؟
Umm... Madam, do you get the wrong girl?
أمي... سيدتي، هل تأتين لك الفتاة الخطأ؟
It's my first day here.
إنه أول يوم لي هنا
I really don't know your husband.
لا أعرف زوجك حقًا
He has a lover here for a long time.
لديه حب هنا لفترة طويلة
I know that.
أعرف ذلك
Or why would he always not go home?
أو لماذا لا يذهب إلى المنزل دائمًا؟
A seductive girl like you
فتاة مغرية مثلك
must be the reason he keeps coming.
لا بد أنه السبب في حضوره باستمرار
Confess. Is it you?
اعترف، حقًا؟
It's really not me.
ليس أنا حقًا
Is it you? Confess.
حقًا؟ اعترف...
No!
لا
Wen Yu?
ون يو؟
Madam, I really don't know your husband.
سيدتي، أنا حقا لا أعرف زوجك
This is actually my lover.
هذا هو حبيبي في الحقيقة
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Why didn't you tell me before you came?
لماذا لم تخبريني قبل أن تأتي؟
You look handsome
تبدو وسيمًا
but have a bad taste.
لكن ذوقك سيء
If this seductive girl is yours,
إذا كانت هذه الفتاة المغرية ملكك
restrain her.
كبحها
Don't let her out so casually
لا تدعها وشأنها دون تكلف كبير
to seduce someone else's husband.
لإغراء زوج شخص آخر
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
Mind your tongue. You must be getting the wrong girl.
اهتم لسانك، لا بد أنك تسيء استخدام الفتاة
She and I love each other.
أنا إنها أحب بعضنا البعض
How would she seduce anyone else?
كيف أغويه أي شخص آخر؟
So indecent.
فاحش جدًا
What? No more acting?
ماذا؟ لا تمثيل؟
Forget it.
انس الأمر
Why do you stare at me like this?
لماذا تحدق بي هكذا؟
Look what you're wearing.
انظري ما ترتدينه
No wonder she got you wrong.
لا عجب أنها أخطأت
What's wrong with my dress?
ما خطب ثوبي؟
And look at you.
انظر إلى نفسك
When you're dressed like this,
عندما ترتدين مثل هذه الملابس
strangers
الغرباء
will think you're a prince.
سوف يظنون أنك أمير
I am...
أنا...
Isn't that...?
أليس هذا...؟
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
I wanted to ask you.
أردت أن أطلب منك
You people have pushed too far.
لقد دفعت الناس بعيدا جدا
Your emperor made me marry
اجعلني إمبراطورك أتزوج
the useless North Prince.
الأمير الشمالي عديم الفائدة
I'm out for a walk. What's the problem?
أنا بالخارج للمشي، ما المشكلة؟
The North Prince isn't as terrible as you think he is.
أمير الشمال ليس فظيعًا كما تظن
I don't care.
لا يهمني
I may not really
قد لا أكون حقا
be the North Princess Consort.
تكون قرينة الأميرة الشمالية
Are you going
هل ستذهب
to run away?
للهرب؟
- I... - Mr. Chen,
- أنا... - سيد تشن
what are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Baihe.
بايهي
Baihe, don't go.
باي، لا تذهب
Baihe, I really missed you.
باي، اشتقت إليك كثيرًا
So, I came to see you.
لذلك، جئت لرؤيتك
Mr. Chen, you lied to me.
السيد تشن، لقد كذبت علي
How do you have the nerve to see me again?
كيف لديك الجرؤ على رؤيتي مرة أخرى؟
I'm a businessman.
أنا رجل أعمال
I shouldn't have lied that I was an official.
ما كان يجب أن أكذب بأنني مسؤول
- Oh, man. - Baihe, let me explain.
- يا إلهي! - باي، دعني أشرح لك
He made up an identity to cheat this girl.
اختلق هوية لغش هذه الفتاة
- What a dirty trick! - I don't want to listen.
- يا لها من خدعة قذرة! - لا أريد أن أصغي
I just don't.
لا أريد الاستماع
Baihe.
بايهي
- He made up an identity. - I'm really wrong.
- شكَّل هويةً - أنا مخطئ حقًا
- Maybe he has a reason for that. - I'm sorry.
- ربما لديه سبب لذلك - أنا آسف - يا إلهي
- Don't ignore me. - What reason can he have?
- لا تتجاهلني - ما هو السبب الذي يمكنه الحصول عليه؟
You're a musician.
أنت موسيقي
I know you always want to marry an official.
أعلم أنك دائمًا تريد أن تتزوج موظفة
Indeed, I'm a musician.
بالفعل، أنا موسيقي
Marrying an official will change my identity.
زواج مسؤول سيغير هويتي
But the love between us
لكن الحب بيننا
can't be as important as such identities?
لا يمكن أن يكون مهما مثل هذه الهويات؟
It's my fault.
إنه خطأي
I underestimated your feelings for me.
لقد قللت من مشاعرك تجاهي
Forgive me this once.
سامحني هذه مرة واحدة
I won't lie to you again.
لن أكذب عليك مجددًا
Musician?
موسيقي؟
- What is a musician? - Really?
- ما هو الموسيقي؟ - - حقًا؟
Yes.
نعم
- Why does a musician want to marry an official? - If you lie to me again,
- لماذا يريد موسيقي أن يتزوج من مسؤول؟ - إذا كذبت عليّ مجددًا
- In Beishuo, a musician is humble. - I won't see you anymore.
- في بيشو، الموسيقي متواضع - لن أراك بعد الآن
- If a musician wants another identity, - I won't.
إذا أراد موسيقي هوية أخرى - لن أفعل
she has to marry an official.
عليها أن تتزوج من مسؤول
This is such a terrible rule.
هذه قاعدة فظيعة
I'll come and see you in a couple of days.
سآتي لرؤيتك خلال يومين
All right.
حسنًا
But you should
لكن عليك أن
tell your father about our marriage soon.
عن زواجنا قريبا
Rest assured.
كن مطمئنا
I won't betray you.
لن أخونك
We
نحن
can go out.
يمكننا الخروج
I...
أنا...
I can't feel my legs.
لا أشعر بساقيّ
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Wait for me.
انتظرني
What a man!
يا له من رجل!
Some girls can't get married
بعض الفتيات لا يمكن لهن الزواج
when they want to
عندما يريدون
while some have to get married
في حين أنه يتعين على البعض الزواج
when they don't want it.
عندما لا يريدون ذلك
Everyone has his destiny.
كل شخص له مصيره
Let's say farewell.
لنقل وداعًا
See you again.
أراك لاحقًا
Ordinary people may choose who they want to marry.
يمكن للناس العاديين اختيار من يريدون الزواج
But if His Majesty knows
ولكن إذا عرف جلالة الإمبراطور
the Eldest Princess of Dongyu will escape against his decree,
الأميرة الأكبر من دونغيو سوف تهرب ضد مرسومه
the consequences will be terrible, huh?
ستكون العواقب وخيمة، هويه؟
I guess the troops will be sent to your state.
أعتقد أن القوات سيتم إرسالها إلى مقاطعتك
They'll search throughout Dongyu.
سوف يبحثون في جميع أنحاء دونغيو
By then, who knows how many
بحلول ذلك الوقت، من يعرف كم عدد
Eldest Princesses will be found?
سيتم العثور على الأميرة الأكبر؟
(So serious?)
(حقًا؟)
Oh, we should do some shopping
يجب أن نقوم ببعض التسوق
for our mansion.
من أجل قصر غيرنا
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدًا
we'll live there for a long time.
سنعيش هناك لفترة طويلة
We need to be well prepared.
يجب أن نكون مستعدين جيدًا
You're familiar with this place. Take us there.
أنت على دراية بهذا المكان، خذنا إلى هناك
Why did you come to the House of Romance?
لماذا جئت إلى مجلس الرومانسية؟
I came with His Highness.
جئت مع صاحب السمو
Your future husband.
زوجك المستقبلي
The North Prince? He's also here?
أمير الشمال؟ إنه هنا أيضًا؟
Where's he?
أين هو؟
I'll go say hello.
سأذهب ألقي التحية
A couple can't see each other before getting married.
لا يستطيع الزوجان رؤية بعضهما قبل الزواج
It's the rule.
هذه هي القاعدة
Such a boring rule.
قاعدة مملة كهذه
Forget it. I'm going back.
انس الأمر، سأعود
Bravo!
شجاع!
You were away for quite a while.
كنت بعيدا لفترة كبيرة
Did any pretty girl hold you up?
هل حملك أية فتاة جميلة؟
Nothing you need trouble yourself about.
لا شيء تحتاجين إليه
Well, I think.
حسنًا أعتقد ذلك
If you fall in love with any girl,
إذا وقعت في حب أي فتاة
let me know.
فهمت
I'll help you get her.
سأساعدك على الحصول عليها
If you don't want me to interfere,
إذا كنت لا تريدني أن أتدخل
I won't trouble myself, then.
لن أزعج نفسي إذن
Come on. Let's drink.
هيا، لنشرب
Gentlemen, thank you for coming.
السادة، شكرا على حضوركم
Miss Su Nian, the unsurpassed lady,
الآنسة سو نيان، السيدة التي لم يسبق لها مثيل
will drink with you.
سوف تشرب معك
Thank you, Miss Su Nian.
شكرا لك، الآنسة سو نيان
Madam Sang,
السيدة سانغ
when will Miss Su Nian
متى ستكون الآنسة سو نيان
dance again?
الرقص مرة أخرى؟
As long as you visit us frequently,
طالما أنك تزورنا مرارا وتكرارا
she'll often dance before you.
ستكون دائما ترقص أمامك
Xingyi,
شينغ يي
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Why are you glaring at her as if she was an enemy?
لماذا تجاهر بها وكأنها عدو؟
She's an enemy.
إنها عدو
Yueling, I've been staring at her for a while.
يويينغ، لقد كنت تحدق بها لفترة من الوقت
I'm sure
أنا متأكدة من أنها
she's the vicious assassin
إنها القاتل الخبيث
who discarded me twice.
الذي تخلص مني مرتين
Assassin?
قاتل؟
Greetings.
تحياتي
I've never seen you before.
لم أرك من قبل
Is it your first visit here?
هل هي زيارتك الأولى هنا؟
Yes.
نعم
Never seen us before?
لم ترينا من قبل؟
But you're exactly that assassin.
لكنك بالضبط ذلك القاتل
Assassin?
قاتل؟
How could Miss Su be an assassin?
كيف يمكن أن تكون الآنسة سو قاتلة؟
You get the wrong girl, I guess.
فهمت الفتاة الخاطئة، أعتقد
I'm a mere dancer in the House of Romance.
أنا مجرد راقصة في دار الرومانسية
That day, you carried me on the horse for a long time.
في ذلك اليوم، حملت لي الحصان لفترة طويلة
I can recognize you, however you change look.
أستطيع التعرف عليك، لكن انظري المتغير
I really don't know what you're talking about.
أنا حقًا لا أعرف ما الذي تتحدث عنه
Yeah, gentleman.
نعم يا رفاق
Do you get the wrong girl?
هل تسئ فهم الفتاة؟
Miss Su Nian has never left here.
سو نيان لم تغادر هنا أبدا
Sorry, Miss Su.
آسفة، الآنسة سو
My brother
أخي
always has face blindness.
دائما يواجه العمى
I guess he's having the problem again.
أظن أنه يتصدى للمشكلة مجددًا
If he offends you, please kindly forgive him.
إذا أساء إليك، أرجوك سامحه
Not at all.
لا على الإطلاق
Maybe I just have
ربما لديّ فقط
a very ordinary face.
وجه عادي جدًا
It's normal that he can't recognize me.
من الطبيعي أن لا يستطيع التعرف عليّ
Hey, you...
أنت...
Sorry.
آسف
A toast to you, dear guests.
نخب لك أيها الضيوف الأعزاء
Hope you'll often come here.
آمل أن تأتي إلى هنا غالبًا
It's her.
إنها هي
Yueling, it's her.
يولت، إنها هي
How can a girl have two faces?
كيف يمكن للفتاة أن يكون لها وجهان؟
She's so good at concealing her identity.
إنها بارعة جدًا في إخفاء هويتها
No wonder she's the unsurpassed lady.
لا عجب أنها السيدة التي لم يسبق لها مثيل
Xingyi, I think Miss Su
شينغ يي، أعتقد أن الآنسة سو
looks gentle and behaves elegantly.
تبدو لطيفة وتتصرف بأنيقة
She isn't like an assassin at all.
إنها لا تشبه القاتل على الإطلاق
Yueling, you don't trust me?
يويلينغ، أنت لا تثق بي؟
I do. Let's get back.
نعم، دعنا نعد
I won't.
لن أفعل
I'll see
سأرى
when she'll give herself away.
متى ستسلم نفسها
Sorry to keep you waiting, Your Highnesses.
آسفة على إبقائك تنتظرين يا أصحاب السمو
Knowing the two princes have come,
بشخصية الأميران قد أتوا
Miss Su Nian is here to propose a toast.
الآنسة سو نيان هنا لاقتراح النخب
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
You may rise.
انهض
Miss Su Nian, tonight,
الآنسة سو نيان، الليلة
you look gorgeous.
تبدين رائعة
You dance even better than before.
أنت ترقص أكثر من ذي قبل
You flatter me, Your Highness.
أنت أجمل يا صاحب السمو
Let me propose a toast to you.
دعني أقترح نخب لك
Indeed.
بالفعل
It's better to watch a pretty girl close.
من الأفضل مشاهدة فتاة جميلة تقترب مني
(Why did I lose my grip at this time?)
(لماذا فقدت قبضتي في هذا الوقت؟)
(I'm really...)
(أنا حقا...)
Shall we rush up or not?
هل نسخر أم لا
He said he would crack a cup to remind us.
قال إنه سيتصدع كوبًا لتذكيرنا
Go.
اذهب
Su Nian, run!
سو نيان، اركض!
Go. Hurry.
هيا، بسرعة
Look, Yueling.
انظر يا يويلينغ
The assassin will finally give herself away.
القاتل سوف يسلم نفسه أخيرا
Come on, Xingyi.
هيا يا شينغ يي
Let's go help Miss Su.
دعنا نذهب لمساعدة الآنسة سو
Don't.
لا تفعلي
I'm sure she can do martial arts.
أنا متأكد من أنها تستطيع ممارسة فنون الدفاع عن النفس
You don't still think she's an assassin, do you?
ما زلت تعتقد أنها قاتل، أليس كذلك؟
Yueling, just watch.
يول، احترسي فحسب
She'll easily kill these guys soon.
ستقتل هؤلاء الرجال قريبا بسهولة
Why is she coming over?
لماذا تأتي؟
Please help me.
يرجى مساعدتي
Don't worry, Miss Su. We both do martial arts
لا تقلق، الآنسة سو، كلانا يمارس فنون الدفاع عن النفس
and we can protect you.
يمكننا حمايتك
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Can't you do martial arts, too?
ألا يمكنك ممارسة فنون الدفاع عن النفس أيضا؟
Why do you need us?
لماذا تحتاج إلينا؟
Don't be so rude to a lady.
لا تكن فظًا مع سيدة
You keep her safe.
تبقيها آمنة
I'll be right back.
سأعود على الفور
Don't move.
لا تتحركي
Isn't he the cowardly man I met in the day?
أليس الرجل الجبان الذي التقيت به في ذلك اليوم؟
Why is he here?
لماذا هو هنا؟
Don't... Don't come over.
لا... لا تأتي
Don't do silly things.
لا تفعل أشياء سخيفة
What?
ماذا؟
The South Prince has really good martial arts.
الأمير الجنوبي لديه فنون الدفاع عن النفس جيدة حقا
You're that assassin.
أنت ذلك القاتل
Don't go.
لا تذهب
Why are you still here?
لماذا لا تزال هنا؟
These assassins after this cowardly man...
هؤلاء القاتل بعد هذا الرجل الجبان
You don't come over.
أنت لم تأتي
- Who are they? - What?
- من هم؟ - ماذا؟
Stay away.
لا تقترب
He can't be the North Prince, can he?
لا يمكنه أن يكون الأمير الشمالي، أليس كذلك؟
Stay behind me.
ابقي خلفي
He's the South Prince.
إنه الأمير الجنوبي
- You know each other? - Don't come over. Just don't.
- هل تعرفان بعضكما البعض؟ - لا تأتي، لا تفعل ذلك فحسب
Not really.
كلا
He tried to save me.
حاول إنقاذي
- But his plan failed. - Don't run.
- لكن خطته فشلت - لا تركض
(You just need to pretend to kill me.)
(عليك فقط أن تتظاهر بقتلي)
(But you idiots)
(لكنك أيها الحمقى)
(keep coming after me.)
(استمروا في المجيء إليّ)
Come on.
هيا
Protect the North Prince.
حماية الأمير الشمالي
That's right. Protect the North Prince.
هذا صحيح، حماية الأمير الشمالي
Run!
اركض!
Too late.
فات الأوان
Again?
أعد ذلك؟
You're such an idiot.
يا لك من حمقاء
Protect the South Prince!
أحمي الأمير الجنوبي!
(This isn't)
(هذا ليس)
(what I planned.)
(ما خططت له)
(Wen Yu, I'll save you.)
(وين يو، سوف أنقذك)
One.
واحد
Two.
اثنان
Yueling, what are you doing?
يول، ماذا تفعل؟
Go with me.
اذهب معي
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery)
(الطقس البارد وتشابك)
Your Highness, Your Grace,
صاحب السمو، غيرك
you're back.
لقد عدت
I packed something else.
حزمت شيئًا آخر
When are we leaving?
متى سنغادر؟
That vicious woman
تلك المرأة الشريرة
has so many tricks.
لديها الكثير من الحيل
She's sometimes gentle and sometimes evil.
إنها لطيفة وأحيانا شريرة
Oh, no.
لا
Is Wen Yu dead?
هل مات وين يو؟
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Why do you look so dazed
لماذا تبدين مجنونة جدا
after you're back?
بعد أن تعود؟
Oh, no.
لا
It must be her.
لا بد أنها هي
I didn't die with him.
لم أموت معه
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدثين؟
Why can I not get it?
لماذا لا يمكنني الحصول عليه؟
So, are we escaping or not?
إذًا، هل نهرب أم لا؟
- No.
- لا
No?
لا
Wen Yu, who escorted me here...
وين يو، الذي رافقني هنا...
He died.
مات
How did that happen?
كيف حدث ذلك؟
He's young. That's too bad.
إنه شاب، هذا مؤسف جدًا
But what does it have to do
لكن ما علاقة ذلك بنا
with our escape?
بهروبنا؟
You don't understand.
أنت لا تفهم
He needn't have died.
لم يكن هناك أي موت
If I had died with him,
إذا كنت قد مت معه
we would be back to life.
سنعود إلى الحياة
Your Grace, the dead can't come back to life.
غريسك، لا يمكن للميت أن يعود إلى الحياة
How can he live again?
كيف يمكنه أن يعيش مجددًا؟
That's not right.
هذا ليس صحيحًا
Nobody else can. But he can.
لا يمكن لأحد آخر ذلك، لكنه يستطيع ذلك
Not alone.
ليس وحده
We can come back to life together.
يمكننا العودة إلى الحياة معا
Forget it.
انس الأمر
I'm going to the North Prince's mansion.
أنا ذاهبة إلى قصر الأمير الشمالي
Your Grace, it's late at night.
غريسك، الوقت متأخر في الليل
It's really inappropriate to see a martial guard
من غير المناسب حقا رؤية حارس قتالي
in the North Prince's mansion now.
في قصر الأمير الشمالي الآن
If you really want to see him,
إذا كنت تريد رؤيته حقا
how about you go tomorrow?
ماذا عن أن تذهبي غدًا؟
You can send an invitation,
يمكنك إرسال دعوة
offering to visit the North Prince
لعرض زيارة الأمير الشمالي
as his bride-to-be.
كعشوة له
But a couple can't see each other
لكن الزوجين لا يمكن لهما رؤية بعضهما البعض
before getting married.
قبل الزواج
What if the North Prince doesn't approve?
ماذا لو لم يوافق الأمير الشمالي؟
Yueling,
يويلينغ
why would Dongyu people like us
لماذا شعب دونغيو مثلنا
obey Beishuo rules?
طاعة قواعد بيشو؟
You're right.
أنت على حق
My top priority
أولويتي القصوى
is to check on Wen Yu.
هي التحقق من وين يو
I can't bother about anything else.
لا أستطيع إزعاج أي شيء آخر
I'll go prepare the invitation, then.
سأذهب لإعداد الدعوة إذن
Hope Wen Yu will be all right.
آمل أن يكون ون يو على ما يرام
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
I failed my job to keep you safe.
فشلت في عملي للحفاظ على سلامتك
I should be punished, Your Highness.
يجب أن أعاقب يا صاحب السمو
Your Highness.
سموك
I'm not dead yet.
لم أموت بعد
Forget it. It wasn't your fault.
انسي الأمر، لم يكن خطأك
Oh, Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
a message was sent from Dongyu.
تم إرسال رسالة من دونغيو
I haven't told you yet.
لم أخبرك بعد
Tell me now.
أخبرني الآن
According to our scout,
وفقا لكشفنا
in Dongyu,
في دونغيو
besides the Eldest Princess,
إلى جانب الأميرة الأكبر
there is another princess.
هناك أميرة أخرى
And her name is Yueling.
واسمها يويلينغ
Ashina Yueling.
أشينا يويلينغ
This young princess is said
هذه الأميرة الشابة يقال
to be always liberal.
أن تكون دائما ليبرالي
Now, she isn't in the imperial palace.
الآن، ليست في القصر الإمبراطوري
Oh, Your Highness.
أوه، يا صاحب السمو
Even more coincidentally,
حتى من قبيل المصادفة أكثر
she has a little brother,
لديها أخ قليل
Xingyi.
شينغ يي
The young prince of Dongyu.
الأمير الشاب من دونغيو
Yueling for Ashina Yueling.
يويلينغ لأشينا يويلينغ
Xingyi for Ashina Xingyi.
شينغ يي لأشينا شينغ يي
Oh, I see.
فهمت
Such a dramatic trick.
مثل هذه الحيل المثيرة
So, she and her brother fooled us.
لذلك، قامت هي وأخوها بخداعنا
No wonder
لا عجب
they helped the Eldest Princess escape.
ساعدا الأميرة الأكبر في الهروب
Have our men watch over Dongyu.
اجعل رجالنا يراقبون دونغيو
Remember.
تذكري
Don't let anyone else know about this.
لا تدع أحدًا آخر يعرف عن هذا
So, you'll marry the young princess
لذلك، ستتزوجين الأميرة الشابة
instead of the Eldest Princess
بدلا من الأميرة الأكبر
and you'll just let it go?
وستترك الأمر يذهب؟
In the marriage,
في الزواج
the bride doesn't really matter.
العروس لا يهم حقا
I must focus on the big picture.
يجب أن أركز على الصورة الكبيرة
Your Highness.
سموك
- Your Highness.
- صاحب السمو
Your Highness, are you injured?
صاحب السمو، هل أنت مصاب؟
You can't die, Your Highness.
لا يمكنك أن تموتي يا صاحب السمو
Injured?
مصاب؟
That's what you've been expecting, huh?
هذا ما كنت تتوقع فعله يا هوه
If only I was injured!
إذا أصبت فقط!
Then I could frame Zhou Shiyu
إذن يمكنني تأطير تشو شيوي
for murdering his elder brother.
لقتل أخيه الأكبر
But what happened?
ولكن ماذا حدث؟
He was stabbed to protect me.
طُعن لحمايتي
Even His Majesty has heard about it.
حتى جلالة الملك سمع عن ذلك
Now, he's meritorious!
الآن، هو مثير للتقدير!
What do you actually want,
ماذا تريد في الحقيقة
to be injured or not to be injured?
أن تُجرح أم لا؟
Of course, I want...
بالطبع، أريد...
Forget it. Doesn't matter.
انسي الأمر، لا يهم
What matters is your terrible self-injury trick
ما يهم هو خدعتك الفظيعة لإصابة نفسك
didn't work at all!
لم تنجح على الإطلاق!
Such an idiot.
حمقاء!
Indeed.
بالفعل
That's right. I'm too incapable.
هذا صحيح، أنا غير قادر جدًا
I can't even be
لا يمكنني حتى أن أكون
as smart as Piggy.
ذكية مثل الأكولة
Or it'll be humiliating the pig.
أم أنه سيكون مهينًا للخنزير
You even want to roast my pig?
حتى إنك تريدين تحميص الخنزير الخاص بي؟
No, no, no. That's not what I mean.
لا هذا ليس ما أعنيه
I don't mean that, Your Highness.
لا أقصد ذلك يا صاحب السمو
Hurry.
هيا
Punish him now!
عاقبوه الآن!
- Yes. - No, Your Highness.
- نعم - لا يا صاحب السمو
I really don't mean that.
أنا حقا لا أعني ذلك
Piggy.
اكولة
Your Highness, you get me wrong.
صاحب السمو، أنت تسيء فهمي
I hate those who love to eat roast pork.
أكره أولئك الذين يحبون تناول لحم الخنزير المحمص
- Your Highness. - Don't be scared.
- صاحب السمو - لا تخف
Tickle him as hard as you can.
قم بتوثيقه بأقصى ما تستطيعين
- All right. - Your Highness.
- حسنًا - صاحب السمو
Don't be scared, Piggy.
لا تخافي أيتها الأكولة
You did a good job.
لقد قمت بعمل جيد
The aggravated contradictions between the two princes
التناقضات المتفاقمة بين الأميران
will drive a feud between them
سوف يؤدي إلى العداء بينهما
and impede the young emperor.
وإعاقة الإمبراطور الشاب
It's my duty to help you, Prime Minister.
من واجبي أن أساعدك يا رئيس الوزراء
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(حفل الأمير الشمالي)
It's my honor to be married to the North Prince by His Majesty.
إنه لشرف لي أن أتزوج من أمير الشمال من قبل جلالة الإمبراطور
I hear the North Prince is handsome
سمعت أن الأمير الشمالي وسيم
and righteous.
وصالح
Everybody likes him.
الجميع يحبه
I want to see him
أريد أن أراه
for my affection and admiration.
لمشاعري وإعجابي
So, I'd like to visit His Highness.
لذلك، أود أن أزور سموه
Sorry for the inconvenience.
آسفة على الإزعاج
Her writing skills are really...
مهاراتها الكتابية هي حقًا...
Naughty.
شقي
Are you sure she's Ashina Yueling,
هل أنت متأكدة من أنها أشينا يويلينغ
the young princess of Dongyu?
الأميرة الشابة دونغيو؟
Yes.
نعم
I double-checked it.
تحققت من الأمر مرتين
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
will you meet
هل ستلتقين
this princess?
هذه الأميرة؟
According to the rule,
وفقا للقاعدة
a couple can't see each other before getting married.
لا يستطيع الزوجان رؤية بعضهما قبل أن يتزوجا
She won't give up before seeing me.
لن تستسلم قبل أن تراها
Then I can see her
إذن أراها
while she can't see me.
بينما لا تستطيع رؤيتي
I get it. I'm on it.
فهمت، سأقوم بذلك
This way, please.
بهذا الطريق، من فضلك
Is there a Mr. Wen Yu
هل هناك السيد ون يو
working for His Highness?
يعمل لصالح سموه؟
Is he here today?
هل هو هنا اليوم؟
Wen Yu?
وين يو؟
It's me, exactly.
إنه أنا، بالضبط
It sounds similar to His Highness's name.
يبدو متشابها مع اسم سموه
But His Highness said it was all right.
لكن سموه قال أن ذلك صحيح
You're Wen Yu?
أنت ون يو؟
But the man I know
لكن الرجل الذي أعرفه
is a young martial guard.
هو شاب من حراس القتال
Someone has the same name?
شخص ما لديه الاسم نفسه؟
Well, a lot of talents
حسنا، الكثير من المواهب
work for His Highness.
تعمل من أجل سموه
I can't recognize them all.
لا أستطيع التعرف عليهم جميعا
The yards here
المسافن هنا
look really pretty.
تبدين جميلة حقا
Yes, of course.
نعم، بالطبع
His Highness is the lineal son of the late emperor
سموه هو ابن الإسقاط من الإمبراطور الراحل
and the youngest brother of His Majesty.
والأخ الأصغر لصاحب الجلالة
He can own all the best things in the world.
يمكنه أن يمتلك كل أفضل الأشياء في العالم
Come this way, please.
بهذا الطريق، من فضلك
Be careful.
انتبهوا
Here.
هنا
I'm here.
أنا هنا
Come.
هيا
You can't catch me.
لا يمكنك الإمساك بي
Be careful.
انتبه
Where are you?
أين أنت؟
House of Pretties?
بيت المؤلفات؟
Who is this house for?
لمن هذا المنزل؟
You have sharp eyes, Miss.
لديك نظرة حادة يا آنسة
Ladies in this house
السيدات في هذا المنزل
(House of Pretties) are all gorgeous.
(بيت الجمال) جميعًا
They are sent from different places.
يتم إرسالها من أماكن مختلفة
According to His Highness,
ووفقا لصاحب السمو
he won't marry these ladies
لن يتزوج من هذه السيدات
until he has a consort.
حتى يكون لديه قرين
Respect to his future wife, you know.
احترام زوجته المستقبلية، كما تعلمين
(This prince)
(هذا الأمير)
(has built a house of ladies a long time ago)
(بنى منزلا من السيدات منذ وقت طويل)
(and thinks he's respecting his future wife.)
(ويظن أنه يحترم زوجته المستقبلية)
(How shameless!)
(كم وقح)
This way, please.
بهذا الطريق، من فضلك
(House of Pretties)
(دار الجمال)
(Stay Modest)
(لا تتدخلي)
Your Highness, the Eldest Princess of Dongyu is here.
صاحب السمو، الأميرة الأكبر من دونغيو هنا
I hear you adore me.
سمعت أنك تحبني
A couple in Beishuo can't see each other before getting married.
لا يستطيع ثنائي في بيشوه رؤية بعضهما قبل أن يتزوج
Did no one tell you about it?
ألم يخبرك أحد بذلك؟
Is that why you see me from behind the curtain?
ألهذا السبب ترينني من وراء الستار؟
When you break the rule,
عندما تكسرين القاعدة
I'll be the one people laugh at.
سأكون الشخص الذي يضحك فيه
Your Grace,
غريسك
I'm sure you can understand,
أنا متأكد من أنك تفهم
can't you?
ألا يمكنك؟
You have your rules
لديك قواعدك
while we have ours.
بينما لدينا قواعدنا
A couple can't see each other here.
لا يمكن لأحد أن يرى الآخر هنا
But that's not the case in our state.
لكن ليس هذا هو الحال في مقاطعتنا
If it's inappropriate, please understand.
إن كان هذا غير ملائم، فأرجو أن نفهم
Unlike what you're said to be like,
على عكس ما يُقال إنك تتصرف به
you have such a quick tongue.
لسانك السريعة
I'm too busy with work
أنا مشغول جدا بالعمل
to care about you, Your Grace.
للعناية بك يا ملك
If you need anything,
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى أي شيء
have someone inform my butler.
أرسل شخصا ما لإبلاغ خادمي
I want someone from you, Your Highness.
أريد شخصا منك يا صاحب السمو
You'll approve, huh?
سوف توافق، هوه؟
Who do you want?
من تريد؟
Wen Yu.
ون يو
Not the butler,
ليس الخدم
but the martial guard.
ولكن الحارس الأصغر
Why do you want him?
لماذا تريده؟
My maid Yueling
خادمة يول
received a lot of help from Wen Yu on her way here.
تلقت الكثير من المساعدة من ون يو في طريقها إلى هنا
So, she adores him.
لذلك، فهي تعتقده
Yesterday, she accidentally heard
بالأمس، سمعت عن طريق الخطأ
Wen Yu was assassinated in the House of Romance
ون يو اغتيل في بيت الرومانسية
and she was really worried.
وكانت قلقة حقا
So, she begged me to come and ask about him.
لذلك، توسلت إليّ لتأتي وأسأل عنه
Your Highness, do you know how Wen Yu is now?
صاحبة السمو، هل تعرف كم هو الآن؟
You sound so anxious.
تتحدث قلقا جدا
I think you actually adore him
أعتقد أنك تحشده في الحقيقة
instead of Miss Yueling.
بدلا من الآنسة يوان ينغ
Yueling adores him.
يول يعشقه
I'm just anxious for her.
أنا قلق عليها فحسب
Tell Miss Yueling
أخبر الآنسة يو ينغ
to forget Wen Yu.
لينسى وين يو
Why?
لماذا؟
Because he's dead.
لأنه مات
Be careful, Your Grace.
كن حذرا يا غريسك
Qianqian,
تشيان
Wen Yu is dead.
ون يو مات
Your Grace, the dead can't come back to life.
غريسك، لا يمكن للميت أن يعود إلى الحياة
Don't hurt yourself.
لا تؤذي نفسك
I got him killed.
تسببت في قتله
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحًا
Go buy me a brazier.
اذهب واشتري لي برازيلية
I'm on it.
أنا عليه
What maid?
خادمة
It's just you.
أنت فقط
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
what did you just say to Her Grace?
ماذا قلت للتو لنتها غريس؟
She looked absent-minded
بدت شاردة الذهن
and couldn't even walk steadily.
ولم تستطع حتى المشي باضطراد
I feared she would bump into a pillar.
كنت أخشى أن تنضم إلى عمود
Nothing.
لا شيء
I don't know what I should burn for you.
لا أعرف ما الذي يجب أن أحرق لك
Here's some paper money.
إليك بعض الأوراق المالية
Enjoy it.
استمتعن بالأمر
And these pretty women of all kinds.
وهؤلاء النساء الجميلات بجميع أنواعه
Pick one as your wife.
اختاري واحدًا كزوجة لك
You didn't
أنت لم تترك قلادتك
leave your jade pendant to me.
تترك قلادة اليشم الخاصة بك لي
I'll then burn
إذن سأحرق
my pendant for you.
قلادتي لك
If you get into trouble in heaven,
إذا وقعت في ورطة في السماء
it may help you.
قد يساعدك
Do you not want to lose the pendant
ألا تريد أن تفقد القلادة
or do you not want to lose me?
أو لا تريد أن تفقدني؟
Wen Yu,
ون يو
if... if you hate this,
إذا... إذا كنت تكره هذا
go find those men who killed you.
ابحثي عن هؤلاء الرجال الذين قتلونك
Whatever you want,
مهما كنت تريدين
I'll burn it for you.
سأحرق لك
I'll burn... I'll burn some paper money.
سأحرق... سأحرق بعض الأوراق المالية
Or anything. Anything you want.
أو أي شيء، تريده
And these pretty women...
وهؤلاء النساء الجميلات...
Pick one.
اختاري واحدًا
I'll burn anyone you want.
سأحرق أي شخص تريده
These women are boring.
هذه النساء مملات
I want you!
أريدك!
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبلة حاجباك ♪
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائمًا في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم ♪
♪Like how we met for the first time♪
♪ مثل كيفية التقينا للمرة الأولى ♪